Now in the early days of AI, there was a lot of excitement and work on logic.
在人工智能早期 人们对从事逻辑工作非常兴奋
Can you give us a bit of historical perspective on the topic.
您可以简单介绍一下这方面的历史吗？
&gt;&gt; AI started in the 50s through the 70s with the idea that what we needed was
— 人工智能始于上世纪 50 年代 一直到 70 年代 人们认为我们需要
better languages and systems for writing down logical statements, and
书写逻辑语句更好的语言和系统
once we have written enough of them, we should be able to do anything.
并且一旦我们编写足够多的逻辑语句 我们应该无所不能
And some things worked great.
其中一些发挥了非常好的效果
We were able to make a program be the best chess player in the world.
我们能够制作出一个程序 成为世界上最优秀的象棋选手
But other projects failed.
但是另外一些项目失败了
And I think there were two main issues.
我认为其中存在两个主要问题
One, it was a mistake to try to make statements only in Boolean logic,
第一 只依靠布尔逻辑编写语句是错误的
where everything is true or false.
布尔逻辑中任何事情非真即假
And that's because the world is uncertain.
这是因为世界充满不确定性
So the logic of probability is a better fit to the world.
所以概率逻辑更适合描述世界
And we didn't get good algorithms for
不过直到 20 世纪 80 年代我们才找到
dealing with probability until the mid 1980s.
处理概率的好算法
And two,
第二
we realized it was too laborious to try to write down everything by hand.
我们认识到手工编写语句费时费力
In the 1990s to the current day, more and
上世纪 90 年代至今 越来越多的
more data was becoming available online, and now we think first of learning
数据可以从网上获取 现在我们首先想到
about the world from data rather than writing rules by hand.
根据数据了解世界 而不是手工编写规则
And still logic has its place.
而逻辑仍具有一席之地
Well how is logic used today?
那么我们今天如何使用逻辑呢？
&gt;&gt; Well there's many domains where we can eliminate much
— 许多领域中我们可以消除
of the uncertainty of the real world and solve significant problems using logic.
真实世界的不确定性 使用逻辑解决重要问题
One example would be a company like FedEx, planning
其中一个例子是联邦快递 (FedEx) 公司
all the deliveries of its packages using its huge fleet of vehicles.
使用大型交通工具 计划所有包裹的托运
We can describe this as a logic problem and
我们可以将它描述为逻辑问题
find a solution that minimizes time and expense.
并且找到时间和费用最小化的解决办法
&gt;&gt; Peter will also be talking about algorithms that are useful for
— Peter 也会探讨一些算法
understanding how expert systems work.
有利于理解专家系统的原理
Expert systems are used throughout the world, and are so
专家系统应用于整个世界
common that most people don't even think about them as AI anymore.
因为非常普遍 以至于人们根本想不到这是人工智能
One famous example is that during the first Persian Gulf War,
著名例子发生在第一次海湾战争期间
one superhuman decision made by one military expert system
某个专家系统做出了超人的决定
about where to place a supply base saved the United States $2 billion, which
设立供应基地的地点为美国节省了 20 亿美元
was more money than DARPA ever invested in artificial intelligence research.
这一数字超过了美国国防部高级研究计划局在人工智能研究方面的投资
One of the things I like about this section is how you and
在这部分中 我希望你和 Sebastian
Sebastian move from logical representations to planning algorithms,
从逻辑表示法转向规划算法
to planning algorithms for when actions or even the world is uncertain.
当行动或世界不确定时的规划算法
What directions do you think we will be seeing for
你认为未来我们
planning algorithms in the future?
规划算法的趋势是什么呢？
&gt;&gt; Well, learning from examples would be an important area.
— 从例子中学习将会成为一个重要领域
Transfer of learning across domains, where we learn to play in one area and
在不同领域中转换学习 即我们在某个领域学会的知识
then execute that in another area.
在另一个领域进行执行
Interactive planning, where human machine team solves problems together,
交互式规划是指人机团队共同解决问题
and a lot of the issues are what's the best
主要问题在于什么是最好的界面
interface rather than just getting the right answer.
而不只是得到正确答案
Being able to work together as a team.
能够在团队中共同工作
And being able to explain things in terms that humans can understand, so
能够以人类可以理解的方式解释事物
that the humans can add things that might have been missed in the original
所以人们可以添加有关问题初始语句中
statement of the problem.
可能缺失的内容
&gt;&gt; In these videos, we are gonna look out for the resolution algorithm.
— 在这些视频中要关注解析算法
It is an elegant way of inferring new knowledge from a knowledge base and
这种方法可以较好地从知识库中推断新知识
is one of my favorite in this section.
也是这部分中我最喜爱的内容之一
Graphplan, which is described in the book reading,
图规划是阅读中描述的内容
was created by Georgia Tech's own Merrick Furst back in 1995, and
由乔治亚理工大学 (Georgia Tech) 的 Merrick Furst 于1995年提出
made planning practical for a whole new range of problems.
可以编写规划 用于解决一系列问题
Finally, value iteration is a key concept for Markov decision processing.
最后值迭代是马尔可夫决策工程的重点概念
Understanding these algorithms is a good school for this section because they
理解这些算法有利于这部分的学习
require a firm foundation in the basics that are being taught.
因为它们要求具备扎实的基础知识